Experience the dark side of nature
Blood Monkey is a action, adventure, horror film directed by Robert Young.
Six American grad students have arrived in Africa to
study apes with a renowned professor.
But after setting up camp in a jungle clearing, they soon become witness to
the carnage inflicted by the strange and remote species.
Professor Hamilton, played by F. Murray Abraham.
Seth, played by Matt Ryan.
Amy Armstrong, played by Amy Manson.
Dani Sudeva, played by Freishia Bomanbehram.
Greg Satch, played by Matt Reeves.
Chenne, played by Prapimporn Kanjunda.
Blood Monkey is a 2007 American direct-to-video natural horror film
produced by RHI Entertainment and directed by Robert Young.
It aired on various video on demand channels, before officially premiering in the United States on
the Syfy Channel (called Sci-Fi channel at the time it premiered) on January 27, 2008.
Filmed in Thailand, it is the first film in the Maneater film
series produced under an agreement with Syfy.
The film followed a group of six students studying primates in Asia under the demented Professor
Hamilton who find themselves under attack from bloodthirsty primates in the jungle.
Reviewers panned the film, criticizing the acting, dialogue, plot, low-quality special
effects, and the lack of appearances by the titular monster, the monkeys.
They also questioned the appearance of F.
Murray Abraham in the film, though note that his
performance was its only positive aspect.
The film explores themes of expedition, mad scientist, jungle, killer ape.
The tone is dark.